这里是警察局  有什么紧急情况
911, what's your emergency?
有人在听吗  有人吗
Is someone there? Hello?
你想要什么
What do you want?
我说  你想要什么
I said, what do you want?
怪奇物语  第三季
第二章
贸鼠
你还好吧
Is everything okay?
嗯
Yes.
你好  这里是维勒家
Hello, this is the Wheelers.
好  等一下
Yeah, just a sec.
迈克
Mike!
有电话
Phone!
知道了
Okay!
你好
Hello?
都9点32了  你在哪呢
It's 9:32. Where are you?
对不起  我  我正准备打给你
Sorry, I-- I was just about to call.
我
I, um...
今天不能去看你了
can't see you today.
什么  为什么不能
What... Why not?
因为我奶奶
It's my Nana.
她的病很严重
She's very sick.
但是霍普不是说你奶奶没事
But Hop said that your Nana was okay,
只是虚惊一场么
that it was a false alarm.
是啊
Yeah.
我们一开始是这么想的
That's... what... we thought it was at first,
但之后她突然病情加重了
but then she took a real turn for the worse.
我们觉得她可能会
Yeah. We think she might...
-死  -什么
- die. - What?
妈  别偷听我们电话
Mom! Get off the phone!
都好几次了
How many times?!
奶奶打电话来了吗
Did Nana call?!
没有  妈  快挂了电话
No, Mom! Just get off the phone!
刚刚的事很抱歉
Sorry about that.
-刚才是你妈么  -是的
- Was that your mom? - Yeah.
她很伤心  她都胡言乱语了
She's so upset, she's making no sense.
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
因为我们要去养老院
Because we have to go to the nursing home.
去看我奶奶
To see Nana.
翻译     老饭  王木木  Monie
-去过之后能来找我吗  -不能
- You can come over after? - No!
我是说  我
I mean, I--
我就是觉得我今天需要静静
I just think... I need to be alone today.
翻译     Vi君  joy_bwl
缓解一下
With my...
翻译     whosrona  若紫末摘花
情绪
feelings?
你在说谎吗
Do you lie?
什么  没有
What? No.
校对     小酸奶
朋友之间不撒谎
Friends don't lie.
妈  你说什么
What, Mom?
时间轴     西查
我妈在叫我  我最好先挂了
My mom's calling me. Better go.
明天再聊  已经开始想你了  拜拜
Talk to you tomorrow. Miss you already. Bye!
后期     8T
总监     小酸奶
怎么了
What's going on?
*他们还常说你不会想去拉超人的披风*
*And they say You don't tug on Superman's cape*
*你不会朝风中吐口水*
*You don't spit into the wind*
*你不会想去扯下一个老独行侠的面具*
*You don't pull the mask on That old Lone Ranger*
*更不会去招惹吉姆*
*And you don't mess around with Jim*
*没错我正在找42号街的头头*
*Yeah I'm lookin' for the king Of 42nd Street*
*他开着一辆顶级凯迪拉克*
*He drivin' a drop top Cadillac*
*上周他抢走了我所有的钱*
*Last week he took all my money*
*这听起来有点好笑*
*And it may sound funny*
*但我是来讨回我的钱的*
*But I've come to get my money back*
*所有人都说土小子*
*And everybody say jack*
情绪已经被分享
Emotions have been shared.
规矩已经定好了
Boundaries have been set.
秩序
Order...
已经
has been...
-恢复  -等等  成功了吗
- restored. - Wait, wait, it worked?
今天是这
This is the first day
漫长痛苦的六个月来
in six long, excruciating months
他们第一次不会见面
that they will not be seeing each other.
没错  我觉得成功了
Yes, I think it worked! Yes!
别  停下
No, stop.
都是你的功劳
It's all you.
我是个傀儡  你才是幕后的人
I'm a puppet, you're the master.
所以你都记下来了
So you remembered everything?
是啊
Yeah, yeah.
我还是即兴发挥了一下  你懂的
I mean, I had to improvise a little bit, you know.
原来找迈克
It turns out, getting to Mike,
才是关键
now that was the key.
你没朝他吼吧
And you didn't yell at him?
我会跟你在晚饭边吃边聊
I'll tell you everything over dinner.
我想我们七点一起去恩佐餐厅
I was thinking, you know, Enzo's, tonight, 7:00.
在你拒绝我之前
Hey, before you say no,
我  我想先说明白
I'd-- I'd like to make one thing crystal clear.
这不是约会
This is not a date.
等等  约会
Wait, a date?
你从没提过什么约会
You never said anything about a date.
我知道  我确实没提过约会
I know, I didn't say anything about a date.
我只是想说清楚
I just wanted to clear it up
省得你产生一些误会
in case there was any confusion on your part.
-没误会  -很好
- There's not. - Great.
就是两个好朋友一起吃顿丰盛的晚餐
It's just two friends getting together for a nice dinner.
这是我们应得的  不是吗
I mean, we've earned it, haven't we?
我不能在外面待到太晚
I can't be out late.
你九点前就能回到家
You'll be home by 9:00.
-八点  -八点半  我去接你
- Eight. - 8:30, I'll pick you up.
-我们到那见  -七点  恩佐餐厅
- I'll meet you there. - 7:00. Enzo's. Meeting there.
就这么定了
Deal.
头儿  收到了吗  头儿
Hey, Chief, you copy? Chief!
我现在有点忙
Yeah, I'm a little busy right now.
市政厅
反对商场
Recall the mall!
本地工作留本地
-我这儿更忙  -反对商场
- Yeah, well, I'm busier here. - Recall the mall!
市长是头猪
爸妈还有还有孩子要喂
你明天还想来上班吗
You wanna keep your job tomorrow,
反对商场
那你就得赶紧给我滚来市政厅
I think you need to get your ass to Town Hall. Now.
公务在身
Duty calls.
天哪
Jeez.
清理一下第五通道
Cleanup on aisle five.
-再见  -今晚见
- Bye. - See you tonight.
朵丽丝·德里斯科尔  康沃利斯路4819号  疾病  老鼠
该死  该死
Oh, shit, shit.
糟糕
Whoopsie-daisy!
小心点  神探南茜  小心点
Careful there, Nancy Drew. Careful.
倒咖啡可不是简单的活  姑娘
Pouring coffee's a tough gig, girl.
您的咖啡  加两勺奶油和两块糖
And here you are, two creams, two sugars.
谢谢  亲爱的
Thanks, sweetheart.
不用谢
Of course.
汤姆
Tom?
我不得不问
I really hate to ask this,
今天你能找别的姑娘
but do you think one of the other girls
给你去买午餐吗
could run and grab lunch today?
她们有工作要忙
They're needed at their desks.
我知道  我只是
I know, I just, um...
我真的得去看医生
I really need to go to the doctor.
我有些女孩子家的问题
I've been having some... girl problems.
-拜托  别漏光  -快走吧
- Oh, come on! The light! - Let's go.
我...
Look, I just...
我不知道这是不是个好主意
I just don't know if this is such a good idea anymore.
真的吗  可我觉得
Really? Because I feel like
这是我整个夏天最棒的主意
it's the best idea I've had all summer.
我只是想说去征求一下他的许可能怎么样呢
Look, all I'm saying is, what harm is there in asking?
怎么样就是汤姆会拒绝
The harm in asking is that Tom will say no.
我们只在事后请求宽恕  不在事先请求许可
We ask for forgiveness, not permission.
只要这报道如我预期的一样好
And if this story's as good as I think it's gonna be,
汤姆就不会在乎
then Tom won't care.
事实上  他还会感谢我们
In fact, he'll thank us.
或是那位老女士被气疯
Or the old lady is nuts
然后这报道完全被我们搅黄了
and the story blows up in our face
汤姆解雇我们
and Tom fires us.
那我们再也不用在这破地方工作了
And then we never have to work at this shithole again.
星庭商场
炸热狗棒
-祝你们过得愉快  -谢谢
- Have a nice day. - Thank you.
我是达斯汀
I'm Dustin.
我是罗宾
I'm Robin.
很高兴见到你  他在这里吗
Pleasure to meet you. Uh, is-- is he here?
你说谁
Is who here?
亨德森
Henderson.
亨德森  他回来了
Henderson! He's back!
-他回来了  -我回来了
- He's back! - I'm back!
你有工作了
You got the job!
我有工作了
I got the job!
你有多少小屁孩朋友
How many children are you friends with?
不  不  不可能
No, no. No way.
比菲比·凯茨还要火辣吗  不可能
Hotter than Phoebe Cates? No.
她特别棒  她根本不在乎
Brilliant, too. And she doesn't even care
我的牙还没长出来
that my real pearls are still coming in.
她说没有牙亲起来更棒
She says kissing is better without teeth.
太棒了  为你骄傲  兄弟
Wow. Yeah, that's great. Proud of you, man.
这  这有点浪漫
That's ro-- That's kinda romantic.
太棒了
That's like... wow.
你真的能随心所欲  想吃多少就吃多少吗
So do you really just get to eat as much of this as you want?
当然了  虽然我不该吃太多
Yeah. I mean, sure. It's not really a good idea for me, though.
我得为了女士们保持身材
I gotta keep in shape for the ladies.
那有什么用吗
Yeah, and how's that working out for you?
-别理她  -她看起来很酷
- Ignore her. - She seems cool.
她不酷  其他傻蛋在哪里
She's not. So, where are the other knuckleheads?
他们昨天抛弃我了
They ditched me yesterday.
-不会吧  -在我回来的第一天
- No. - My first day back.
-你敢信吗  -真的吗
- Can you believe that shit? - Whoa. Seriously?
对天发誓
I swear to God.
等他们无法共享我的荣耀
They're gonna regret it, though, big time,
他们会后悔的
when they don't get to share in my glory.
荣耀  什么荣耀
Glory? What glory?
昨晚
So, last night,
我们试着与苏茜联系
we're trying to get in contact with Suzie...
我...
And, uh...
香橙果子冻和巧克力
...and the orange sherbert and chocolate.
我截获了一份苏联的秘密通信
I intercepted a secret Russian communication.
什么
What?
我截获了一份苏联的秘密通信
I intercepted a secret Russian communication.
说大声点
Just speak louder.
我截获了一份苏联的秘密通信
I intercepted a secret Russian communication!
天啊  小声点  我知道你说什么
Jeez, shh. Yeah, okay, that's what I thought you said.
那意味着什么
What-- What does that mean?
意味着我们可能会成为英雄  史蒂夫
It means, Steve, we could be heroes.
真正的美国英雄
True American heroes.
美国英雄
American heroes.
你可以想要多少女人就有多少女人  还有更多
Just think, you could have all the ladies you want and more.
-更多吗  -更多
- More? - More.
我喜欢更多
I like more.
我们要怎么办
What's the catch?
没怎么办  我需要你的帮助
No catch, I just need your help.
帮什么
With what?
罗曼诺夫英俄互译词典
帮我翻译
Translation.
该死
Shit!
我们能谈谈吗
Can we talk?
他说  他想我
And then he said he-- he missed me.
然后就挂电话了
And then he just hung up.
-他是个混蛋  -什么
- He's a piece of shit. - What?
迈克今天什么事都没有
Mike doesn't have jack shit to do today,
他奶奶显然没有生病
and his Nana obviously isn't sick.
我保证他和卢卡斯正在玩雅达利
I guarantee you, him and Lucas are playing Atari right now.
但朋友之间不撒谎
But friends don't lie.
没错  可男朋友会撒谎
Yeah, well, boyfriends lie.
无一例外
All the time.
她知道我在撒谎  她知道我在撒谎
She knows I'm lying. She knows I'm lying.
-我根本不懂为什么要撒谎  -因为霍普
- I don't even understand. Why lie? - Hopper.
他威胁我
He threatened me.
-他说过会杀了你吗  -什么  没有
- Did he say he'd kill you? - What? No.
-那有什么可担心的  -我担心的是
- So then, what's the big deal? - The big deal is
如果我不照他说的做  他就不让我见一一了
if I don't do what he says, then he'll stop me from seeing El.
永远不让我见了
Like, permanently.
你不明白  卢卡斯  他疯了
You don't understand, Lucas. He's crazy.
他疯了
He's lost his mind.
朋友们  我这边马上准备好了
Hey, guys, I'm almost set up here.
我别无选择  卢卡斯  我真的别无选择
I had no choice, Lucas. I really had no choice.
我只是希望你有问过我的意见
I just wish you'd consulted me,
因为你这件事处理得
because the way you handled this,
真的糟透了
you're in deep shit.
你不能再打电话给他了
You're going to stop calling him.
也不要接他的电话
You're going to ignore his calls.
对你而言  他不存在
As far as you're concerned, he doesn't exist.
不存在
Doesn't exist?
他把你当垃圾
He treated you like garbage.
你也要把他当垃圾
You're gonna treat him like garbage.
让他自食恶果
Give him a taste of his own medicine.
自食恶果
Give him the medicine.
如果他不好好弥补
And if he doesn't fix this,
如果他不解释为什么
if he doesn't explain himself,
就把他甩了
dump his ass.
我说实话  会很惨的
I'm not gonna lie, it's gonna be bad.
但是
But...
你能弥补这事
you can fix this.
这只是一个小错误
It's just one little mistake.
我犯过几百个  上千个
I've made hundreds, thousands.
麦克斯甩过我整整五次
Max has dumped me five times.
而我是怎么做的
But what have I done?
我有自暴自弃吗  没有
Have I despaired? No.
我重振旗鼓
I've marched back into battle,
而且我每次都赢回了她
and I've won her back every single freaking time.
-怎么做到的  -我教你
- How? - I'll show you.
来吧
Come on.
-我们去哪里  -去找点乐子
- Where are we going? - To have some fun.
生活比那些傻男生更有趣  你知道的
There's more to life than stupid boys, you know.
等等  伙计们
Wait, guys!
我还在这儿呢
I'm still here!
伙计们
Guys?
不准丢东西  柯蒂斯
No dunking, Curtis.
不准
No...
丢东西
dunking.
天啊  就连她的声音都让我好烦
God, even her voice annoys me.
就像指甲刮黑板
Nails on a chalkboard.
别担心  女士们  坚持十分钟就上场了
Don't worry, ladies, ten more minutes till showtime.
莉兹  能帮我涂下背吗
Liz, will you get my back?
吉尔  我要去上厕所
Hey, Jill, I gotta use the restroom.
你能帮我看着霍利吗
Will you watch Holly for me?
-当然  亲爱的  -谢谢
- Sure thing, hon. - Thanks.
危险
储藏化学品
比利
Billy?
我
I...
你完全有理由生我的气
I understand if you're angry with me.
我只是
I just...
我想解释
I wanted to explain...
为什么昨晚我没来
...why I didn't come last night.
不是因为你  只是
It's not you, it's just...
我已经有家室了
I have a family.
我不能做伤害他们的事
And I can't do anything that will hurt them.
你能理解的  对吗
You can understand that, right?
但我不该说
But I shouldn't have said that--
比利
Billy.
Billy...
拜托了  你能说说话吗
Please, will you talk to me?
离我远点  凯伦
Stay away from me, Karen.
你看起来不错  比利
Looking good, Billy.
下午好  比利
Afternoon, Billy.
我能尝尝薄荷糖吗
Can I try the peppermint stick?
你还没尝过薄荷糖吗
Haven't you already tried the peppermint stick?
尝过了  但我想再试一次
Yes, and I'd like to try it again.
史蒂夫
Steve!
你觉得怎么样
So what do you think?
-听着很耳熟  -什么
- It sounded familiar. - What?
音乐  结尾那里的音乐
The music. The music right there at the end.
你为什么在听音乐  史蒂夫
Why are you listening to the music, Steve?
听俄语
Listen to the Russian!
-我们在翻译俄语  -我在努力听俄语
- We're translating Russian! - I'm trying to listen to the Russian,
-但有音乐啊  -好了  托管时间结束
- but there's music-- - All right, babysitting time is over.
你得过去了
You need to get in there.
我的白板  那可是重要的数据  蠢蛋们
Hey, my board. That was important data, shitbirds.
我向你保证  我们正在做的事
I guarantee you, what we're doing
比你的数据重要得多
is way more important than your data.
是吗  你又怎么知道
Yeah? And how do you know
这些俄语绝对不是什么好事
these Russians are up to no good anyways?
-她怎么知道俄语的事  -我不知道
- How does she know about the Russians? - I don't know.
-你告诉她了  -不是我
- You told her about-- - It wasn't me.
我听得见你们在说什么
Hello, I can hear you.
实际上  我全都能听见
Actually, I can hear everything.
你们俩声音都超级大
You are both extremely loud.
你们觉得你们录下了
You think you have evil Russians
邪恶苏联人密谋破坏我国的证据
plotting against our country, on tape,
你们想翻译出来  但一个字都没搞明白
and you're trying to translate, but haven't figured out a word
因为你们不认识
because you didn't realize
苏联人的字母表和我们的天差地别
Russians use an entirely different alphabet.
是这样吗
Sound about right?
-你觉得你在干吗呢  -我想听一下
- What do you think you're doing? - I wanna hear it.
-为什么  -因为也许我能帮上忙
- Why? - 'Cause maybe I can help.
-我精通四国语言  你知道的  -俄语
- I'm fluent in four languages, you know. - Russian?
我的天
Holy shit!
那是隐语  呆瓜
That was Pig Latin, dingus.
-傻瓜  -但是我会说西班牙语
- Idiot. - But I can speak Spanish
法语和意大利语
and French and Italian,
而且我在乐队待了十二年
and I've been in band for 12 years.
我的耳朵可灵了  相信我
My ears are little geniuses, trust me.
求你了  你该去卖冰淇凌了
Come on, it's your turn to sling ice cream,
该轮到我来翻译了
my turn to translate.
我不是想逞功  我只是好无聊
I don't even want credit. I'm just bored.
德里斯科尔
有事吗
Yes?
-你是德里斯科尔夫人  -是的
- Mrs. Driscoll? - Yes?
你好  我叫南茜  南茜·维勒
Hi, um, I'm Nancy. Nancy Wheeler.
我们昨晚在电话里简单聊过
We spoke briefly on the phone last night.
我们是《霍金斯邮报》的记者
We're from The Hawkins Post.
是的
Oh, yes!
老天
Oh, my goodness.
你们年纪轻轻竟然就是记者了
Oh. You look too young for reporters.
很多人都这么说
We get that a lot.
跟我来
Follow me.
房子真漂亮
Oh, it's... it's lovely.
你一直一个人住这吗
Do you live here all alone?
是的  我的丈夫杰克
Yes. Jack, my husband,
他去世到如今有十年了
he passed away, what is it now, ten years ago.
我很抱歉
I'm... I'm so sorry.
没事
Oh, don't be.
我还挺喜欢清静的生活
I kinda like the quiet.
至少曾经清静
At least, I did.
这边请
This way.
就在那边
It's right over there.
肥料
你们看到那些小牙印了吧
You see those little teeth marks, don't ya?
这些袋子
And... these bags, um...
你确定它们之前都是装满的
you're sure they were full before?
我还没老糊涂呢  亲爱的
I'm old, honey, not senile.
我上周二才从布莱克本商店买回来的
Bought them over at Blackburn's Supplies just last Tuesday.
你们来给我解释解释
Now you tell me,
为什么老鼠会偷吃
why would rats want to eat
一位贫穷老奶奶的肥料
a poor old woman's fertilizer?
你确定是老鼠干的吗
Are you sure they did?
也许它们只是咬坏了袋子
Maybe they just gnawed the bag? I mean...
偷吃肥料似乎...
eating fertilizer seems...
太疯狂了  相信我  亲爱的  我懂
Crazy. Believe me, I know, honey.
但
But...
这些老鼠不太对劲
something's not right with these rats.
你到底想表达什么
What does that mean, exactly...
"不对劲"
"Not right"?
我猜是狂犬病
Rabies, my guess.
于是我就在想
That's when I said to myself,
"多丽丝  你得叫报社的人来
"Doris, you gotta call the paper.
如果这些病鼠到处乱跑
Because if those diseased rats are runnin' loose,
人们应该要知道"  难道你不这么想吗
the people, they oughta know." Wouldn't you agree?
对了  我忘说了
Oh, yes, I forgot to mention!
到这边来
Come on over here.
我抓到了一个小混蛋
I caught one of the little bastards.
臭猪克莱恩  臭猪克莱恩
Kline's a swine! Kline's a swine!
臭猪克莱恩
Kline's a swine!
支持城区
臭猪克莱恩
臭猪克莱恩  臭猪克莱恩
Kline's a swine! Kline's a swine!
臭猪克莱恩
Kline's a swine!
吉姆
Jim?
克莱恩市长在等你了
Mayor Kline is ready for you.
好的
Great.
谢谢
Thank you.
吉姆
Jim.
谢谢你能来一趟
Thanks for coming by.
我是不会帮你的  拉里
I'm not doing it, Larry.
冷静点  你根本不知道我想干什么
Calm down, now. You don't even know what I want.
你讨厌你的粉丝俱乐部
You don't like your fan club,
你想叫我让他们闭嘴  没说错吧
you want me to shut 'em down. Sound about right?
你什么时候变得这么严肃了
When'd you get so serious?
坐下吧
Take a seat.
你所谓我的粉丝俱乐部
My fan club, as you call them,
你知道他们为什么在外边抗议 对吧
now, you know why they're out there, don't ya?
他们不是粉丝吗
They're not actually fans?
他们因商场丢了工作
They lost their jobs to the mall
又责怪这是我促成的
and blame me for helping make that happen.
现在
Now,
你去问问城里的他人
you go ask anyone else in this town.
他们都喜欢这个商场
They all love the mall.
这帮助了我们的经济增长
It's helped our economy grow,
增添了新的就业岗位
brought in new jobs,
还有一些很不错的新商店
and just some incredible new stores.
这就是为什么他们
Which is why they all stopped
都不再去小便利店购物了
shopping at their, uh, mom-and-pops.
那不是我的问题  吉姆
Now, that's not me, Jim.
这不过一群老式美国资本主义者
That's just, uh, good old fashioned American capitalism.
拉里  我觉得他们也不过是在演练
Well, Larry, I think that they're just exercising
他们的老式美国抗议权
their good old fashioned American right to protest.
是的
I agree.
-好的  -不过
- Yeah. - If.
他们得有许可才行
If they had a permit.
如果我说错了你可以纠正我  但吉姆
Now, correct me if I'm wrong here, Jim, but, uh...
我相信他们没从你那拿到过许可
I don't believe they secured a permit from your office,
对吧
did they?
据我所知  没有
Not that I'm aware of.
那我相信我有权驱散他们
Then I do believe it's within my right to get rid of them.
拉里
Larry,
我不玩政治
I'm not a politics guy,
但我觉得如果你强行无故驱散外面这些人
but I think if you force those people out of here without provocation,
这会对你连任竞选不利
I don't think that's a good look for your re-election campaign.
你知道四天后是什么日子吗  吉姆
You know what's in four days, Jim?
独立日
Independence Day?
没错
That's right.
我会在这个小镇举办有史以来最盛大的庆典
And I'm gonna throw this town the biggest bash it's ever seen.
烟火  音乐  各种活动  应有尽有
Fireworks, music, activities, you name it.
我会全力以赴  你知道这是为什么吗
I'm gonna pull out all the stops. You know why?
因为最终
'Cause at the end of the day,
选民只会记得这个
that's all the voters will remember.
但是外面那么吵
But I can't think, much less plan,
我没法思考  更别说策划了
with all that racket going on out there.
所以  如果你不介意的话
So, if you don't mind,
麻烦你...
please...
做好你的工作
just do your job.
亮亮你金色的小警徽
Flash your little gold badge,
把他们赶走
and get rid of them.
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
星庭商场
怎么了
Hey, what's wrong?
人太多了
Too many people.
违反规则了
Against the rules.
你是认真的吗
Seriously?
你有超能力
You have superpowers.
再糟能糟到哪去
What's the worst that could happen?
那我们先去干什么
So, what should we do first?
你从来没来过商场吧
You've never been shopping before, have you?
那看来我们得每样都试一试了
Well, then I guess we're just gonna have to try everything.
走吧
Come on.
我只是不明白我们在找什么
I just... I don't understand what we're looking for.
那种好看又亮晶晶能表示"我很抱歉"的东西
Something pretty and shiny that says "I'm sorry."
什么  要找写着"我很抱歉"字样的东西
What, just something that literally says "I'm sorry"?
不
No!
你喜欢那个吗
Do you like that?
我怎么知道  我喜欢什么
How do I know... what I like?
穿上试试
You just try things on.
直到你找到你自己的风格
Until you find something that feels like you.
我的风格
Like me?
对
Yeah.
不是霍普
Not Hopper.
不是迈克
Not Mike.
是你
You.
梅维达
《静态电磁设备》《电磁理论基础》
《电磁概念及应用》
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
拜尔斯夫人
Mrs. Byers?
你要是继续闹的话
We're gonna have to keep doing this
我们就得一直僵持下去  小混蛋
until you stop moving, you little shit.
罗安除虫
你好  我是《霍金斯邮报》的南茜·维勒
Hi, yes, um, this is Nancy Wheeler from The Hawkins Post.
对...
Yeah, um...
我要问的问题可能有点奇怪
I have a bit of a weird question for you.
我想问一下
I was wondering if you
你们最近有没有接到关于
guys had gotten any recent calls about, um...
狂犬病老鼠的电话
rabid rats?
不  狂犬病老鼠
No, uh, rabid rats.
得了狂犬病的老鼠
Rats with rabies?
好的...
Okay, um...
那普通的老鼠呢
What about just rats, in general?
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
你还真是个小侦探  是吗
You're a regular little detective, aren't ya?
要柠檬汁吗  现榨的
Lemonade? It's fresh-squeezed.
好  谢谢
Sure, thanks.
你介意我再打几个电话吗
Do you mind if I make just a few more calls?
完全不介意  有人陪着挺好
Not at all. I enjoy the company.
安德森粮种
布莱克本商店
你还好吧  小家伙
You all right, little bud?
乔纳森
Jonathan!
我有线索了
I have a lead.
好  但是...
Yeah, okay, but, uh...
我只是觉得这只老鼠真的不太对劲
I just think there's something really wrong with this rat.
还用你说
Yeah, no shit.
-快走  -不  我...
- Come on. - No, I...
南茜  等等我
Nancy, wait up.
我问你们想要什么
I said, what do you want?!
建造
To build.
我要你建造
I want you to build.
建造什么
To build what?
你所见的
What you see.
我不明白
I don't understand.
I don't understand!
你什么意思  我不明白
What do you mean? I don't understand!
老兄
Hey, man!
比利  你没事吧
Billy, are you okay?
比利
Billy?
Billy.
带我去找他
Take me to him.
什么
What?
我问你是不是受伤了
I said, are you hurt?
发生什么了  我听到尖叫声
What's going on? I heard screaming.
要我叫救护车吗
Should I call an ambulance?
比利
Billy?
你好  先生
Excuse me, sir.
这个泰迪熊多少钱
How much for this teddy bear right here?
三百块
Three hundred?
Three hundred.
我应该把那个泰迪熊直接塞到他的
I should've shoved that teddy bear right up his--
迈克
Hey, Mike.
哈什照相馆
就是这样  姑娘们
That's it, girls!
好了  准备
Okay, here we go.
请换衣服
Wardrobe change, please!
换衣服了  谢谢
Wardrobe change! Thank you!
晃起来  摇起来
Shake it. Shake it out for me.
快走
Come on!
看  我跟你说什么来着
See? What'd I tell you?
有很多比愚蠢的男孩子更有趣的事
There's more to life than stupid boys.
现在我们能玩龙与地下城了吗
Can we please play D&D now?
-不行  -不行
- No. - No.
等等  最后那段  再放一遍
Wait, that last part, just one more time.
好吧
Okay.
那个词  是什么来着
Okay, that word. Um...
是念作"迪利纳亚"
It's pronounced... "Dly-nna-ya."
-"迪利纳亚"  -是怎么拼的来着
- "Dly- nna- ya..." - Which is spelled...
是这个椅子  这个长得像椅子一样的字母
The-- The chair. The chair-looking thingy.
好的
Yeah, okay.
-我们把第一句话翻出来了  -真的
- We've got our first sentence. - Oh, seriously?
对啊  "这周很长"
Yeah. "The week is long."
真令人激动
Well, that's thrilling.
我知道  不过还是有进展
I know. But, progress.
来  你们点的
Okay, here you go, you got
一个草莓的  一个香草糖屑的
a strawberry and then a vanilla with sprinkles,
-多加奶油  -谢谢
- extra whipped cream. - Thanks.
等等
Wait a second.
你能来这里吗
Are you even allowed to be here?
那什么
That...
行吧
Okay.
你想换着吃吗
You wanna trade?
这太荒谬了  我为什么就不能
That's ridiculous. Why can't I just...
这是在逗我吧
Oh, you've gotta be shitting me.
-我们没那么多  -那我们平摊呢
- Haven't got that much. - Okay, what if we split it?
平摊什么  这根本没道理
Split it with what? Does that even make sense?
真是没想到啊
Isn't this a nice surprise.
你在这干吗
What are you doing here?
购物
Shopping.
这是她的新造型
This is her new style.
-你觉得怎么样  -你脑子坏了吗
- What do you think? - What's wrong with you?
你知道她是不能来这的
You know she's not allowed to be here.
她是什么  是你的小宠物吗
What is she, your little pet?
对啊
Yeah.
-我是你的宠物吗  -什么  不是
- Am I your pet? - What? No!
-那你为什么把我当垃圾  -什么
- Then why do you treat me like garbage? - What?
-你说奶奶病了  -对啊  她病了
- You said Nana was sick. - She is.
她就是病了
She is. She is sick.
-对  她生病了  -她生病了
- Yeah, sick-- she's sick. - She's sick.
她病得很严重  这其实也是我们来这的原因
She's super sick. That's why we're here, actually.
对  我们是来购物的
Yeah, we're shopping.
不是给我们自己买  而是帮奶奶买
Not for us, but for her, for Nana.
-帮奶奶买的  -而且我们还想给你买个礼物
- For Nana. - Also, we're here to get a gift for you.
只是我们找不到什么适合你的东西
Just, we couldn't find anything that suited you
而且我只有大概三块五  挺难买到合适的
and I only have, like, $3.50, so it's hard.
超级不容易
Super hard.
东西都很贵
It's-- It's expensive.
你骗人
You lie.
你为什么骗人
Why do you lie?
我要甩了你
I dump your ass.
-我们现在能玩龙与地下城了吗  -不能
- Now can we play D&D? - No.
吉姆  他把我的财产税涨了
He raised my property taxes, Jim.
把我从我自己的地盘上撵走
Forced me off my land.
亨利  你可以想怎么抗议就怎么抗议
You can protest all you want, Henry,
但前提是你要通过合法的渠道
you've just gotta go through the proper channels first.
那个男人对我们所做的一切都不合法
Nothing proper about what that man did to us!
-对我们小镇做的也不合法  -好好好
- To our town! - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
快件专送
Special delivery!
太好了
Ooh, yeah.
是你要的那件吗
That the right one?
是的
Yeah.
对就是它
Yeah!
局长  你这还挺花哨
That's a lot of color for you, Chief.
这是时尚潮流  好吗
It's cutting-edge stuff, all right?
这可是时尚潮流
It's cutting-edge!
我先来一杯双倍苏格兰威士忌
I'll start off with a Scotch, you can make that a double.
好的  先生
Very good, sir.
然后再来一瓶红酒
And I think we'll have a bottle of red, as well.
好的  先生
Very good, sir.
你这的"鸡安蒂"干红怎么样
And how's your "Chee-anti"?
-我们的基安蒂干红是很不错的  -基安蒂
- Our Chianti is quite good. - Chianti.
中瓶的  蕴藏一丝樱桃的甜香
Medium-bodied, with just a hint of cherry.
棒极了
Great.
女人都喜欢樱桃
Women love cherries, huh?
请给我们上两个杯子谢谢
All right, we'll have that and two-- two glasses, please,
一个我用  一个给即将到来的女士
one for, uh, me and one for the lady.
好的  先生
Very good, sir.
这是个什么
And what is this again?
这是一个螺线管
This is a solenoid.
就是一个弹簧包裹的金属芯
It's a coil, wrapped around a metallic core,
当有电流通过它的时候
and when electricity passes through it...
它周围会形成一个电磁场
It creates an electromagnetic field.
正是
Exactamundo.
现在有意思的来了
Now for the fun part.
-我们开始  -好
- Shall we? - Yeah.
我什么也没看见啊
I... I don't see anything.
对
Nope.
你看不见  但我向你保证  电磁场已经形成
You can't see it, but it's there, I assure you.
我们自制的克拉克-拜耶斯电磁场就形成了
Our very own Clarke-Byers Electromagnetic Field.
很棒吧
Pretty neato, huh?
是的
Yeah.
这个电磁场可以影响到它周围的任何带电物体
And this field affects any charged object in its vicinity.
-比如我的磁铁  -比如你的磁铁
- Just like my magnets. - Just like your magnets.
那为什么至今没什么反应
Okay, why is nothing happening?
那是因为我们的电磁场很稳定
Oh, because our field is stable.
然而  一旦我们减小电流
But, if we reduce the current...
这...
How...
磁场的两极
The magnetic dipoles tried
根据力场而改变  但是
to orient according to the field, but--
不  我是说这怎么会发生在我家
No, no, no, I mean, how is this happening at my house?
你想听真话吗
You want my honest opinion?
你的某个孩子半夜起来
One of your kiddos got up in the middle of the night,
撞上了冰箱  把吸盘撞松了
bumped into the fridge, and knocked the suckers loose.
那梅维达的磁铁呢
And the magnets at Melvald's?
-幻想性错觉  -幻什么错什么
- Apophenia. - Apo-what-o-whah?
幻想性错觉  就是
Apophenia. Uh...
你看到其实不存在的东西  巧合罢了
You're seeing patterns that aren't there. Coincidence.
但是万一
But what if...
不是这种情况呢
it's not?
那么
Well...
从理论上而言
Theoretically-speaking,
我猜测有某种大型交流电转换器存在
I suppose some large version of this AC transformer could exist.
某种机器吧
A machine of some kind.
机器
A machine?
但是要同时影响到你家和镇中心  老天
But, in order to reach your house and downtown, gosh,
那得耗费几十亿伏特的电压
that would take billions of volts of electricity
这需要花几千万美金
and cost tens of millions of dollars.
但是依然可行
But it is possible.
1953年我们还治好了小儿麻痹症
We cured polio in '53.
1969年登上了月球
Landed on the moon in '69.
正如我跟学生们讲的
As I tell my students,
一旦你开启好奇的大门
once you open up that curiosity door,
一切皆有可能
anything is possible.
海员勺  冰淇淋店
"这周很长
"The week is long,
银猫进食
the silver cat feeds,
当蓝在西边遇到黄"
when blue meets yellow in the west."
我说
I mean, it just...
这肯定不对
it just can't be right.
-这是对的  -说实话我觉得这是大新闻
- It's right. - Honestly, I think it's great news.
这怎么就成大新闻了
How is this great news?
看来做美国英雄没戏了
I mean, so much for being American heroes.
-完全是一派胡言  -不是一派胡言
- It's total nonsense. - It's not nonsense.
太具体了  很明显是密码
It's too specific. It's obviously a code.
-什么意思  -就像秘密超级间谍密码
- What do you mean, a code? - Like a super secret spy code.
-解释得太牵强  -这可不好说  真的吗
- That's a total stretch. - I don't know, is it?
你信吗
You're buying into this?
听着  以防万一
Listen, just for kicks,
我们得考虑这可能确实是
let's entertain the possibility
秘密的苏联电报
that it is a secret Russian transmission.
不然你以为他们会说什么
What'd you think they were gonna say,
"中午发射导弹"吗
"Fire the warhead at noon"?
-是啊  -我的翻译是对的
- Exactly. - And my translation is correct.
我很确定  所以
I know that for sure, so...
"喂喂银色的猫"谁会这么讲话
"The silver cat feeds." Why would anyone talk like that
除非他们是想掩饰
unless they're trying to mask
-信息的真正含义  -没错
- the meaning of their message? - Exactly.
为什么有人要掩饰信息的真正含义
Why would anyone mask the true meaning of their message
除非这条信息某种程度上非常敏感
unless the message was somehow sensitive?
没错
Exactly.
-我想你的怀疑是对的  -邪恶苏联人
- So I guess that confirms your suspicion. - Evil Russians.
我真不敢相信我马上要同意这个怪孩子
I can't believe I'm about to agree with this strange child, but,
但是没错  绝对是邪恶苏联人
yeah, totally evil Russians.
我们该怎么破解
So how do we crack it?
我想我们翻译完剩下的部分
Well, I guess we translate the rest
希望能找到规律
and hopefully a pattern emerges.
规律  对
A pattern. Right, like
就像"银色的猫" 可能是个接头点
maybe "Silver cat" Is a meeting place?
或是一个人
Or a person.
或是一件武器
Or a weapon.
可能得让一个超级天才来破解  但是
It's probably gonna take a super genius to crack it, but...
史蒂夫呢
Where's Steve?
史蒂夫
Hey, Steve.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我需要25美分  你有25美分吗
Uh, it's a quarter. I need-- Do you have a quarter?
你确定你到年龄可以骑马马了吗
Sure you're tall enough for that ride?
25美分
Quarter!
印第安小马
要不要我扶你起来  小史蒂夫
You need help getting up, little Stevie?
你来能不能闭嘴好好听
Would you two just shut up and listen?
我去
Holy shit.
这音乐
The music.
音乐
The music!
我不懂
I don't understand.
录下来的就是这首歌
It's the exact same song on the recording.
可能俄罗斯也有这种马
Maybe they have horses like this in Russia.
《印第安纳小飞人》  我
"Indiana Flyer"? I don't...
我觉得不对
I don't think so.
这串密码  不是来自俄罗斯
This code, it... didn't come from Russia.
而是来自这里
It came from here.
您是否需要点主菜呢  先生
Would you like to order your entrée, sir?
知道么  恩佐
You know what, Enzo?
我不叫恩佐
My name is not Enzo.
我没胃口了  好吗
I just lost my appetite, all right?
给你吧
So, here you go.
不用找了
You can keep the change.
先生
Sir!
恐怕您不能带着酒离开
I'm afraid no alcohol is allowed off the premises.
我想干吗就干吗
I can do anything I want.
我是警察局局长
I'm the chief of police.
比利  你还好吗
Billy, are you okay?
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
很快就会结束的
It'll be over soon.
别乱动
Just stay very still.
不
No!